[Music]
Welcome to the busy central launch
edition related to 2025 release wave 2.
My name is Alexander Totovich and
together with my colleague Milit Jukich,
she will present what is new in
documents related to Tukfair format in
Germany. Before we explain what truthfer
format is, I would like first to go a
little bit deeper into what PDF A3
format is because Trufford is based on
PDF A3 and this is new format we enable
new functionality we enabled recently in
business central. So PDF A3 is standard
format for long-term arriving of
electronic documents and it allow
embedding any file type into the PDF. So
in sukford we are doing with with XML
but you can embed any any file format
there. This is ideal for hybrid
documents to keep human readable format
as a PDF so you can read as a human pin
but in the same time this is machine
readable for specific electronic
documents. This ensures self-contained
files. So there is no external
dependencies and as you can see this is
widely used in invoicing
especially in Germany for tukair. This
is something what we use in France for
factor X and some other countries.
So what we will deliver in trou in the
business central we are covering both
processes on sales side and purchase
side. So if you're working on a sales
tuk functionality will use all standard
German requirement rules. So everything
what is related with uh uh extren or ple
it will exist in s functionality as
well. So it enables creation outgoing e
documents in sufare format. So that
means we will create pdf based on report
layout with embedded xml inside and send
through any channel you choose. So you
can send through some of existing
connectors or via email.
On a purchase side, we enable receiving
inbound e documents in format. So once
when you get it, system will
automatically extract embedded XML and
process and create continue to create
purchase documents. But on the other
side, this PDF will be attached as a
human readable documents in e documents.
So you can look in both on PDFs to
understand what is inside. and in the
same time proceed with a a machine
readable format of XML and continue to
process with documents. So main business
values there are you will be completely
compliant in Germany. So now with the
souk we support all formats in the
Germany and this is something that will
improve interability and accuracy for
all your documents and uh it will be
really good so you can use any type of
format in a system without any problem.
So military you can show us a demo.
>> Thank you Alexander. Now I will continue
and show you how to proceed with zuker
files in business central. We will start
from exporting part of e documents and
we will start from sales uh process. I
will create in the first company I will
create one sales invoice.
I will choose one customer
and add some item lines on the document.
We can insert some quantity,
some line discount.
Then I will choose another one of the
items and quantity.
Now when we prepare our sales invoice,
we can post it.
And once our sales invoice is uh posted
we can go to related e document and
verify it. We can see that e document is
proceeded and we have some logs. In logs
we can see that our zuper file is
exported and we can check how it is
look. When we open this PDF file, as my
colleague Alexander mentioned, this is a
PDFA type of the document which includes
uh print out of the invoice
uh in PDF uh format and also includes
attachment where we have zuker XML file.
Now as we finished with the sales part
we can go to another company and do the
import of our e document.
I will go to e documents
and choose the new one. Here we choose
zuker format. I will import the same uh
pdf file.
And here we can see that we have created
new document which is currently in in
progress document status.
Uh we have attached um a purchase
invoice the print out of it. And now if
we are okay with this creation of e
documents we can reprocess document.
Once we click on reprocess our new
purchase invoice is created.
and we can verify if everything looks
okay.
Now I want just to remind you about um
necessary setup that we need to
prepare for e document working with zer
files.
So here on e document service for zuk
first format we need to enable bio
reference mandatory and also to choose u
bio reference from where we will take we
can take it from the customer card or
from your reference on document and that
was all from my side. Now I will hand it
over to Alexander. Thank you minisera
for this great presentation. And one
thing I would like to remind you uh it
is important to know that now especially
in a German market you can automatically
send all e documents via email. So once
when you create uh when you have created
if you choose post to send system will
automatically create an email and send
it. It will be available for 27 version.
So that means from this uh 25 release
wave two. Okay. Before we close this
session, I would like to remind you use
all these links. You can find many
important information there. Please do
not forget to subscribe on our LinkedIn
channel to track all news what we are
doing there on a weekly basis and
announcements and watch more videos on
YouTube. So you can use AKMSBC YouTube
to find not only videos from this
edition but for previous editions as
well. Thank you for watching the
fession.